Dennis Drueck — Full-Stack Developer

Naperville, IL GitHub | Portfolio | LinkedIn (872) 228-5265 denwa.dev@gmail.com

About

With 4 years of software development experience and 16 years in IT, I can readily excel in any environment. My diverse background spans multinational corporations like Tesla and E. & J. Gallo, as well as start-ups and freelancing.

I've resolved numerous complex problems, prioritizing scalability and client experience. Most recently, I created future-proof solutions for process automation at Martial Arts Technologies, using Node.js and Express.js, circumventing hundreds of hours of labor.

I'm dedicated to continuous growth and am constantly looking for fresh obstacles to overcome.

Skills

Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, SQL, Java, Python, Bash, PowerShell, SCSS, CSS, HTML

Frameworks: Spring Boot, Node.js, Express.js, React.js, Next.js, Redux, Bootstrap, Tailwind

Databases: PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, MongoDB Atlas

Tools: Git, GitHub, Docker, Kubernetes, Jira, Postman, DevTools, Figma, Adobe XD,

VS Code, IntelliJ, PyCharm

Topics: Agile, CI/CD, REST API, Sessions, Caching, Unit Testing, Performance Testing,

HTTP, TLS, SSH, DNS, SEO, Jamstack

Experience

Full-Stack Developer, Self-Employed

2021-Present

- Provide end-to-end solutions, including full-stack development, UI and UX design, SEO, market research, and digital media, using an Agile approach to build web applications.
- Release products on time by identifying highest value features after evaluating problem statements and distilling requirements in collaboration with product teams.
- Increase traffic and revenue for clients, achieving top SERP rankings and enhancing user experience through excellent page speed, accessibility, and responsiveness.
- Deliver features rapidly, iterating with Agile sprints.
- Improve stability with nearly instantaneous version updates by implementing CI/CD pipelines using Git and GitHub to easily deploy new production builds in seconds.

Full-Stack Developer (Contract), Martial Arts Technologies

2022-Present

Environment: PHP, JavaScript, MySQL, Laravel, Blade, Node.js, jQuery, Bootstrap, CSS3, HTML5, Bitbucket, Jira, cPanel

• Contribute to SaaS products for event management in collaboration with the CTO and the product manager to improve functionality and implement time-saving automation.

- Reduce support requests for cross-platform issues by implementing responsiveness and input validation for 50+ web pages using PHP, Blade, ¡Query, and Bootstrap.
- Increase SERP ranking and page speed via network and asset optimization strategies.
- Automate time consuming tasks related to logo color extraction by scraping CDNs and analyzing images with JavaScript, Node.js, color-thief and tinycolor2.

Full-Stack Developer (Contract), TrapMonkie.io

2021-2022

Environment: JavaScript, React.js, Redux, Redux Thunk, Node.js, Webpack, Jest, SCSS, Git, GitHub, Cloudflare Pages, Ethereum

- Created and maintained a single-page application to facilitate blockchain transactions in collaboration with the product manager and 1 additional developer.
- Delivered MVP in 1 week, and 2 major updates within 1 week of requirements approval.
- Imported real-time data and performed asynchronous transactions via Ethereum's JSON RPC API using web3.js, providing error-proofing and ease-of-access.
- Optimized cross-platform user-experiences with responsive and adaptive design, lazy-loading, and asset optimization.

SaaS Interactivity Specialist, Text2Drive

2019-2021

Environment: JavaScript, Python, Bootstrap, Selenium, CSS3, HTML5

- Owned development, deployment, support, technical client relations, and in-house training related to all SaaS widgets deployed to 200+ auto dealership websites.
- Delivered exceptional user experiences, overhauling widget assets using JavaScript,
 HTML, CSS and Bootstrap, focusing on unifying visual identity with host sites.
- Reduced time-to-delivery by 50% by restructuring cross-company deployment pipelines.
- Enhanced client-experience with proactive communication and well-prepared proposals, backed by my expertise in HTML and CSS, as well as analytics and market research.
- Conserved 40 hours per month by automating toilsome tasks with Python and Selenium.

Education

FastTrack Developer Program, Cook Systems | Certificate

2022-2023

- Studied design patterns and developed full-stack applications using Git, GitHub, Java, Spring Boot, PostgreSQL, JavaScript, React.js, Node.js, CSS, and HTML.
- Met all deadlines and fulfilled client requirements while leading a team of 3 developers.
- Built multiple full-stack applications through 1-week sprints in Agile teams.
- Ensured version stability by reviewing, testing, and merging git branch pull requests.

Project: Twitter Clone API | GitHub

Environment: Java, PostgreSQL, Spring Boot, Maven, Spring Web, Lombok, MapStruct, JPA, JDBC, Postman, Git, GitHub

 Created a REST API web service with Java Spring, including 30 HTTP endpoints to CRUD data related to accounts, tweets, hashtags, likes, follows, replies, and reposts. • Implemented services, data models, repositories, and controllers using Spring Boot and JPA, including data validation, error handling, and reusable functions.

Project: Spotify Artist Guessing Game | GitHub

Environment: JavaScript, Node.js, React.js, React Router, Material UI, howler.js, Lodash, Git, GitHub

- Developed a stateful browser game, allowing users to play songs and guess the artist by fetching genres, artists, and songs from Spotify Web API.
- Implemented capability to play again with fresh data by creating configurable components and routes using React.js, Material UI, and React Router.
- Resolved edge cases for smaller genres through caching and query retries, manipulating and persisting data with HTML Web Storage and JavaScript.
- Enabled users to easily play and switch between songs with a single click by utilizing howler.js and React.js Hooks to control .mp3 playback and global volume.

Project: Company Management Portal | GitHub

Environment: Java, Spring Boot, Maven, Spring Web, Lombok, MapStruct, JPA, JDBC, PostgreSQL, JavaScript, Node.js, React.js, React Router, Postman, Git, GitHub

- Built a full-stack application that allows users to edit employees, announcements, teams, and projects using React.js, Java Spring, JPA, JDBC, and PostgreSQL.
- Clarified client expectations to ensure all features aligned with the customer's needs, creating distinct objectives for developers.
- Provided the front-end team with ample time to deliver a polished interface, distributing tasks effectively to finish 17 REST API web service HTTP endpoints in under 24 hours.

Bachelor of Fine Arts, University of Illinois Chicago

2012

• Studied web design, design thinking, visual communication and perception theory.

Certifications

FreeCodeCamp.org | Certificate

2021-2022

Each below certification included 300 hours of coursework and 5 certification projects.

- Back-End and APIs Express.js, MongoDB, Node.js
- Relational Databases PostgreSQL, Bash
- Front-End Libraries React.js, Redux, jQuery, Bootstrap
- **JavaScript** Data Structures and Algorithms
- **Python** Scientific Computing
- Responsive Web Design Semantic HTML5, CSS3

Additional work history and references are available upon request.